hello my name is green and welcome back
to the last episode of her Mycroft in
1.30 no it's not the last episode
hermitcraft but it is the last episode
in the current version that's right we
are updating today and that's a pretty
big deal for many many reasons one of
which is that some of the things are no
longer gonna work but the biggest thing
for me is going to be that the videos
will look a bit different as you guys
know I actually have a bit more of a
brighter version of Minecraft so once we
update my videos may look slightly
darker and maybe a little bit weirder
until I can get my hands on the tools
that I use for recording and I won't be
able to do this this is like my favorite
thing I can zoom in I can zoom in on so
many things like ah I'm gonna miss that
and it's gonna be really annoying but
it's gonna be worth it to go to 114 this
scale has actually been working on
Sahara over here and I haven't helped at
all I think he's been making like a Zen
garden courtyard type thing which is
really cool I really like this all the
upside-down leaves and the water works
it looks nice either way we're gonna
head over into 114 and I thought we
could take off not upwards like these
Rockets have but we could make our way
there in style
now obviously the server has to go down
for a few hours and then get back up so
I thought what we could do is we could
start heading over to the 1:14 area
goodbye 113 goodbye my beautiful
lighting for a little while and goodbye
the zoom goodbye my zoom function it
will be back as soon as Optifine is
updated but we won't get beautiful
things like this for a while it's gonna
go back to like the grid pattern and all
sorts you'll see you'll see when we get
there anyway let's head over to 114 I
knew I wasn't gonna manage it first time
I thought I could have I thought I can
hop in the boat okay here we go
there we go why am i taking damage there
we go this is pretty smooth now all we
got to do is wait the machine is going
to take us all the way to the 114 chunks
this is exciting journey to 1.14 let's
go by my calculations we should be
nearly there we've been flying on this
thing for a really really really long
time about six thousand blocks is where
that up hello
we got so far how did this happen I'm
guessing it's just going without me
brilliant brilliant come on get the boat
down at the boat town I can't place the
pie I'm not giving up I've made it this
far I'm gonna make it to the border if
it kills me
yes there we go we're back on oh thank
goodness they're all here wait am I the
last one to arrive hey guys
Hey are you telling me that in the last
to arrive yeah by a long way how did you
guys in style there was a tunnel
we prepared a vault I've been on this
for hours
hahahaha don't worry I'm nearly at the
border as you can see just let me just
let me hit ball let me have my moment
oh let's let Greene shatter the border
yeah I'm gonna break three guys I'm
gonna Ram it yes get ready the Balder
will break any minute any second now any
second now just give me give me a second
give me a second
way that actually works I'll see you
later nerds I'm still going stay
together we're going for village okay no
distractions that's our mission he's
gonna explain what's going on then why
are we all here are we missing someone
[Music]
[Laughter]
okay I was gonna say Spence can you
dispense neighbor II know you have to
follow your villager and see where you
live my village is stuck in a barrel
this is his house okay so that was
pretty manic and I feel like I need to
explain what the plan is here because
I'm not sure it was too clear I now
fully understand after some of the other
guys explained it basically you know
where the shopping district is we are
currently 8,000 blocks away from it
8,000 blocks and everything over there
is technically in 113 you know the
chunks and stuff we're not gonna have
berry bushes we're not gonna have these
new villages villages appear around it
because it's already been done so if we
want to get to the new content we have
to come all the way out here 8,000
blocks away
so we thought why not create a portal to
a outpost which is this place called
hermit Ville I I I'm calling it hermit
Ville I don't know if anyone else is
gonna call it by that but I'm gonna call
it hermit Ville and we're not gonna move
here we're not moving house or anything
we're just while we're setting up with
all the 114 shenanigans it's gonna be a
fun to just take a little break from the
shopping district and everything and
move here just for a little while while
we set up and get our hands on all of
the new content and we thought while
we're doing this while we're having fun
let's transform a village let's grab a
couple of villages for ourselves and see
what happens so basically this is the
outpost we're gonna get some new 1-14
content and we're gonna have a lot of
fun doing it I hope that makes sense and
I'll tell you what it's gonna be a lot
of fun because there's about ten people
all in a tiny village and you know on
hermit craft there's gonna be
shenanigans afoot
I've already claimed my house over here
this is villager Gran's house it is tiny
six blocks in size I'm gonna have to
transform this and make this a bit more
useful I don't know where my village is
gone for all I know he's already died
but the idea is that we protect him we
keep him safe and we keep building this
little village up you've lost one guy
already great he's gone I don't know
where he is he's gonna die
it's been like maximum two hours dude
this guy but I thought maybe just taking
the head off cuz you're off the server
do you hear that yep anyway you guys
happen to have put your houses on the
same row as my one here I've claimed
this one down the end which ones have
you guys got you've got mumbles got that
one and it's got the beautiful done one
here yeah and then stress stresses
stresses caused a division among us yeah
all right well I think since all three
of us are here plus stress
I guess stress is our guest here but
what if we call this Sahara Street right
and we label this this is the snow mr.
Horace tree and you know I think that
there's a business opportunity here
because everyone's gonna be living here
for a little while no one's like
permanently moving but we're gonna be
hanging out here for a while because of
all the 1.14 glories that we need to get
our hands on why don't we set up like a
proper Sahara outpost in hermit Ville to
sell things that people might need like
rockets etc so they don't have to keep
going back to the shopping district
diamond I love it dying lovers like
immediately you're like rockets I don't
know maybe we can sell some shocker
boxes some Rockets that kind of thing so
yeah and we can we can take expensive
prices because the the people buying out
here they're like they're stranded
desperate so down the end why don't we
make that the Sahara shop there yeah and
we will make it just like Sahara in
miniature that is me after eating a
little bit more food Jay what just
really worrying me a little bit there's
not more villagers in the village at all
no I'm really hoping we really haven't
lit this place up people kind of just
came in claimed their houses then left
no seriously
all of these houses are empty there's
one guy over here with a profession I
think my guys are rich I claimed two
villages and I think both of them have
died
out of his mouth oh that is not good
that wasn't needed great right in my ear
it's a tongue that's gross guy as well
he's loving and I yeah I think I've lost
both of my villages I'm gonna have to
carry the one I've got a nametag can we
name tag them I've got I've got know for
everyone you normally can't yes you can
yes really
mumble plays minecraft in 110 still
nametag these guys there's yours
this girl 85 wait I've got an idea with
this guy again check this out this guy
this guy's gonna be conquered I thought
that was action release I'm sorry I
thought this was you what can I say he
looks just like you did you guys put a
wither skull on this guy yeah I put up
with her head on him yeah he's pure evil
dude he shouldn't be around here I need
to go and grab a green head I'll be
right back agree and I found your
visitor no yeah and I like why he's
alive and I know why is not nowhere - oh
my goodness it's a it's a horrible sight
dude
Idina belong in a box and he said that
my villager was was kidnapped where's is
it's gonna be a thing we're just gonna
start kidnapping each other can we do
that can we kidnap another time another
time another time shush I'm stealing
everyone's two pages look in here I
don't I don't that is that Oh
unbelievable right I mean and then that
is me I'm so glad that you guys found
him I can't believe Falls stole him lost
him again wandered off this way yeah
just like me we're gonna get on just
fine
in this village any more time to boat
him back to my home yeah wonderful
really awful back there gran can you
take off your helmet please I want it I
want to take in this this horrific
you've got a mate behind you as well
there's two greens
no you have to plop him out now and you
have to wait till nighttime let him yeah
replace the bed and that stuff you don't
have a bed in the house for him Green he
didn't have one you didn't have a bed in
here right come on then my bed right
well my guys in his home now you got you
guys got yours in your home yes - bed
this is gonna be fun
this is gonna be a lot of fun given a
little bit of time it looks like
everyone has actually started settling
in doc has made the tiniest house I love
that and he's actually put his head on
they look so silly and he's actually
done something that I was gonna do here
so you see these berry bushes mobs don't
like walking into them for some reason
well obviously they take damage but it
just means they just stop here and don't
walk into them which is brilliant so I'm
thinking I could actually make a doorway
right here and that way my villagers
should in theory stay inside his house
and be safe and I can get in even if I
do take a little bit of damage so if I
make this a berry bush in theory if I
knock this down he shouldn't try and
pass find out of it so village agreein
is completely safe in there and I can I
can do that but this could be actually
used on a bigger scale you see we could
keep him safe by creating a boundary of
plants maybe like this
in theory this means we can create a
little garden for our villager so he
might come out the back here or he might
just stay in there these villages tend
to be quite stupid well there's a garden
there if he does want to go out it's a
little bit annoying to walk through but
it'll do for the time being but now we
need to decide what we're going to do
with this house and he'll that we have
village agreeing all settled in oh he's
gone into the garden and now he's come
back again well it was close enough it's
hurt it's only been a day and s cow has
built an entire massive house he's
already completely transformed his house
this is insane it's been a day so Horace
tree is 3 village houses and then one
big one now I think personally I've
built in this style for so long this
entire season think about it my base the
gteen base and now Sahara I think I'm
going to avoid this block palette
because I've just used it too much what
I think I'm going to do is try my best
to keep this kind of style you know with
the sort of rustic feel if you like and
we're gonna make this a bit better so I
want to try my best to keep this design
but I do think we need a bit more space
in here as there is only six blocks it's
not very much at all so what I'm
thinking is we extend this out the back
we do some overall improvements and we
see what that looks like oh no no no no
no no no no no okay that doesn't work at
all that doesn't work at all I thought
they didn't go through it but they do
another way to get in actually now that
I think about it I have a much better
way to get in that doesn't involve
taking any damage I just created a one
block high door all I got to do is this
and I'll crawl in you can't get out
you're stuck in here but I'm not and you
can just crawl through or it could even
do the same and just crouch through I'm
such an idiot
I assumed that this works the same he
can't get through this block here and
all I got to do is crouch under it
this is actually
really useful for creating doors that
mobs can't get through and it doesn't
even look that bad but anyway let's
crack home with improving this house I
definitely don't want to rush anything
so I'm gonna take this really slowly
over the next couple of episodes but
I've got a few ideas on how to just
improve this here and now in its current
shape and form just by doing a few
extensions a few detail changes and then
we'll take it from there in the future
we may change this entire thing entirely
over the course of the next few episodes
but for now let's just do some general
improvements and I think we should even
add in some of the new things like
lanterns there's not a lot of space for
this house so I really feel like we're
gonna have to extend it all over I think
we're gonna have to extend this one
quite a lot further back for a start in
a really strange way this feels like a
fresh start because going and getting
all my resources take such a long time
you've got to go through the portal
through the nether and trust me flying
in 114 is not as easy because the chunks
just don't load as fast it's really
frustrating so it's it's a real pain to
travel anywhere which means I've started
collecting a lot of stuff I can't just
pop on over to the shopping district as
easily anymore so to start with let's
just increase the size of this by a tiny
tiny amount just one
well it'll be two blocks on the inside
but it should make it feel a lot bigger
that's already a massive improvement for
in here green jr. you've got a lot more
space to do whatever it is you do what
do you do you make swords and stuff for
expensive prices I like you you're just
like me you're overcharged for
everything I mean fair prices for
everything I've made just a couple of
adjustments and I think it's actually
gone really well but there's one
technique that I wanted to show you guys
because what we're gonna do is we're
gonna create a tiny little berry farm
now I haven't even made a farm and I've
already got a stack of berries so this
might not be necessary at all but what
we do or what we're going to do is place
a bunch of berries in a line like so
maybe a couple of lines and then what
we're going to do is
add a little pergola over the top now in
the past the way that I've done these is
with signs but we've got a new block
called the campfire and it looks like
this it's pretty intense but if you grab
yourself a bucket fill it with water
what you can do is you can extinguish
and take away the water and then you're
just left with the wood now this is
really really cool because it means we
could create some nice effects using the
fireplaces now unfortunately there's a
lot of damage taking involved both with
I shouldn't have put the berries here
first but you see yeah I'm gonna get rid
of the heat we're gonna hear it of these
you can place them in a line like this
and then obviously when we take the fire
away and there's no danger of fire
spread here not only do we get a really
nice pattern underneath like this once
all the fire is gone it's gonna have a
nice pattern this way and from the top
as well which is really really cool now
in theory these lasts forever but if you
break them they do just turn into coal
that really doesn't look healthy does it
so now all I've got to do is go through
each of these and remove the fire there
we go and the effect is really quite
nice now that I think about it though it
definitely looks better from this angle
so maybe I should have had them go that
way rather than the way I've done it you
know the opposite direction so instead
of long ways like this they should go
across but I think you get the idea on
what this looks like now that does look
incredibly flat so I'm thinking what
might look quite nice is a spruce fence
across here to make it look like it's a
bit more supported I think that looks
really really cool and then with the
berry bushes it actually looks like a
bit of a farm and then maybe add a path
here I'm getting all kinds of ideas just
from these couple of blocks that have
been added into the game this is going
to be so much fun to experiment with and
look that's added a lot to my house it's
only a little bit on the side here and
although the
post I might need to move the Sahara
Street sign a little bit but you get the
idea
how much that's improved my house
already and I really want to take this
to the next level so what can we do to
improve this building well for a start
we can extend it out this way a tiny bit
now we don't want to touch stresses
house here because she won't appreciate
that at all now as I said we're taking
things slow to begin with but I think
we've made quite a lot of progress in a
very short amount of time to improve our
house and oh boy am I going to work on
making this the most epic villager house
that you've ever seen
go on villager grin you've got a bit
more space now you can go and explore I
think that's good enough for now I don't
really want to do too much more I want
to think about the design a little bit
more I think that looks really really
cozy even if it is still quite small but
that looks really nice I I would live in
a little cabin like that and I hope
Green jr. is going to enjoy his stay in
here now I don't think I can let him out
I actually don't think this is his house
at all so I think if I let him out he's
never gonna come back so I've got to be
a little bit careful but there is
definitely more space remember when we
started there was six blocks of space
and we've managed to make a bit more
without making the house look too much
bigger and also something terrible has
happened do you remember earlier in the
video there was a villager running
around with a wither head on well he's
that this one's got a green head but
there was another one I swear there was
one down here with the wither head he's
turned it yeah
this guy has turned into a zombie and
this guy's got my head so I think that
was who's caused it and he's turned this
guy into a zombie villager now we can
actually leave him down here in hid in
his cave because he's not gonna be
hurting anyone except me if I don't get
out so he's kind of safe down here
unless anybody kills him and then we can
cure him later on I believe so maybe
we'll do that in the future although I
really wish I really wish no I really
ah no no let me out there we go I really
wish they didn't put the wither head on
him because he looks I don't know if I
want to save it we should we just keep
him as a zombie down there I don't think
we we need him we've got loads of
villagers around but anyway I think
that's where we're going to leave
today's episode I think we've spent a
lot of time coming to the 1.14 hermit
ville and we have established sahara
street remember what this looks like
everybody as it is now after the first
episode in the 1:14 update because i
have a feeling that it's gonna change a
lot i'm gonna try and keep the original
features but let me know in the comments
what you would like to see this become
some massive structure where it all
feels like it's the borough from high
polity know like all holding on to each
other by stilts or should I tear this
down and make something completely new
but this is a really just a nice style
it just feels more homely than the stuff
that I've been making I'd rather live
here than in his cows house I'll be
honest well thank you very much for
watching everyone
I do hope you've enjoyed this video and
let me know what you thought in the
comments below
goodbye